

# **VERONICA CORTES**

## **UI/UX DESIGNER**

#### CONTACTS



- in https://linkedin.com/in/vcortes1976/
- https://vcortes1976.github.io/portfolio/

#### **SKILLS**

- Competitor analysis
- User personas
- User flows
- Iterative wireframing
- Prototyping
- Usability testing
- Interaction design
- Responsive web design
- Style guides
- Basic HTML and CSS

#### **TOOLS**

- Sketch
- InVision
- Figma
- PhotoShop
- Miro
- Usability Hub
- Atom
- GitHub
- GitHub Desktop

### **PROFILE**

Based in London with a background in event management. There are many parallels between event management and UI/UX design with customer/user experience at the very heart. I approach my work with empathy, always putting myself in the users shoes first, and I am passionate about creating positive change through simple and meaningful interface designs which are easy to navigate.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CO-FOUNDER & DESIGNER**

Yoga Kind Collective, London | Jul 2020 - to date

- Designed and launched the brand in conjunction with an online launch event, attended by 65 students based in the U.K, Europe, U.S and Asia.
- Successfully raised funds to secure operational costs to run a series of regular online yoga classes for a minimum of one year.
- Collaborating with Its Mental, a UK based mental health and wellbeing organisation, delivering online yoga programmes to their members.

#### **EVENT DIRECTOR**

Outsourced Events, London | Feb 2017 - Mar 2020

- Nurtured and developed strong client relationships with 5 key accounts in the IT industry, whilst ensuring the continuation and enhancement of event services and delivery worldwide.
- Worked collaboratively with Marketing leads and contractors to create impactful event brand designs, enhancing customer journeys and generating new business leads.
- Trained and mentored junior executives, supporting them in their career development.
- Promoted to Director in March 2019.

# **VERONICA CORTES**

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate in UI Design

CareerFoundry, May 2020 - Mar 2021

Yoga Teacher Training RYT 200

The House of Yoga, Jan - Jul 2020

BA (Hons) Dance

Bath Spa University, 2009 - 2010

Foundation Degree, Dance Theatre

**Performance** 

City of Bristol College, 2007 - 2009

#### **AWARDS**

#### 2010

Lloyds Banking Group Ambassador

#### 2009

**HBOS Reward & Recognition** 

#### 2008

**HBOS Group Top Achiever** 

#### 2006

**HBOS Group Top Achiever** 

# CONFERENCE OPERATIONS MANAGER

Campden Wealth, London | Jul 2016 - Feb 2017

- Successful delivery of exclusive Family Office and Family Business
   Conferences in San Francisco, London, Hong Kong and Abu Dhabi.
- Improved operational efficiencies and collaborative practices by implementing an online project management tool and email marketing tool.
- Designed relevant event collateral to enhance customer experiences, adhering to very strict brand guidelines to uphold brand identity and reputation.

#### **CONFERENCE PRODUCER**

Future Insights, Bath | Jan - Dec 2015

- Worked closely with industry experts to curate and deliver a series of engaging conferences and workshops for designers and developers in London, New York, San Francisco, Boston and Las Vegas, achieving and
- Successfully negotiated 150+ speaker and media partnership agreements from top experts to rising stars.
- Supported in-house designer on all print design including programmes,
   speaker contracts, name badges and branded give aways.

### **TESTIMONIAL**

"As a conference speaker, my interactions with Veronica were treated not only beyond professional, but warm like we'd known each other for years. Veronica is a true testament to what an event organizer should be, putting the individual she's working with at ease, concern-free and taking care of in times you need it most—often before you even realize it's needed."

Cat Noone, Co-Founder and Chief Design Officer, Liberio